SHIVAM PANDEY

8454038839 • shivampandey2903@gmail.com • linkedin.com/in/shivam-pandey-a99296213 •

ClickMe=>"My Portfolio"—- "Socials"—-"Github"—-"Leetcode"

SUMMARY

Computer Science student with experience in Full Stack MERN development, Blockchain developer and Data Science role. I had developed complex web applications that are both functional and aesthetically pleasing. I am confident in my ability to succeed any development role.

EDUCATION

B.Tech, Computer Science Engineering

Graduating May 2024

University of Mumbai,

8.7 GPA

Vidyavardhini College, Vasai

Relevant coursework: System Design OOPS DSA, Operating System Computer Networks SDLC

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Web development: React JS, Next JS, Node JS, Javascript, Node JS, CSS

Block Chain Development: Solidity, Truffle, Ganache, Web3 JS

Programming: Python, C, C++ Database: MongoDB, MySql

Tools: VsCode, Remix IDE, MetaMask, Github

EXPERIENCE

Social Summer of Code (SSOC 23), Hack2skill: Contributor

June 2023 – Aug 2023

- Contributed as well as added my own project FIR system on the blockchain while collaborating with the team.
- Expanded my network and contributed to meaningful projects that impact the broader developer ecosystem.

Codesoft, IT, Consulting: Data Science Intern

June 2023 - July 20223

- Used statistical models to analyze,preprocess,train dataset .(Numpy,Pandas,Matplotlib,Scikit-learn,GCollab)
- · Collaborated with a talented team of data scientists.

ACADEMIC PROJECTS

Decentralized Complain Registration system

May 2023-present

Collaborated in a team of three to design a Fir System on Blockchain.

- Enhanced security, fosters decentralization, ensures immutability of records, and provides transparency.
- Making a great solution for maintaining a trusty tamper-resistant system for registering and managing complaints.

Fitness Website Fall 2022

Build a Perfect Gym Companion website using various Apis.

Ensured team compliance to Design Control Procedures according to Code of Federal Regulations (CFR)

Spring 2022

Led team of three to design and develop an Algorithm Visualizer

- Allows users to interact with mind-blowing visualizations and animation.
- Can control the animation speed, pause or resume the execution, serves as an Educational tool
- Implemented all types of Sorting algorithms, N Queen, Dfs Bfs A*, Binary tree, Path Finding.

ACTIVITIES

BitByte Go(Vcet)

Dec2022- Present

Multiple leadership roles

Algorithm Visualizer

Organized events and designed contests to encourage students in competitive programming

Airnova(Vcet) Dec2020-2022

Multiple roles

• Trained and worked on Ai model for Gesture control Drone using open cv.